<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">
  <channel>
    <title>JournalLM</title>
    <link>https://github.com/TangentFoxy/JournalLM/</link>
    <description>I can't believe I'm doing this. Random journals + NotebookLM "podcasts" = this slop.</description>
    <itunes:image>https://github.com/TangentFoxy/JournalLM/JournalLM.jpg</itunes:image>
    <item>
      <title>2024 Year-End Review &amp; Plans</title>
      <link>https://tangentfoxy.github.io/JournalLM/2024%20Year-End%20Review%20%26%20Plans.html</link>
      <description>These journal entries from November 2023 and January 2024 document the author's daily life, including media consumption (YouTube videos and a film), personal projects (creating custom Magic: The Gathering cards and a technology dependency chart), and self-improvement goals (tracking steps and writing weekly, monthly, and yearly reviews). The entries reveal struggles with maintaining a consistent review schedule and lapses in self-care, along with plans for future tasks and technology-related projects within a Minecraft world. The author also notes missing information and expresses concern about several self-care tasks. The entries show a blend of personal reflections and practical to-do lists.</description>
      <enclosure length="5926944" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://tangentfoxy.github.io/JournalLM/2024%20Year-End%20Review%20%26%20Plans.mp3" />
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2024 00:00 MST</pubDate>
      <itunes:duration>574</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:episode>2</itunes:episode>
      <itunes:image>https://tangentfoxy.github.io/JournalLM/2024%20Year-End%20Review%20%26%20Plans.png</itunes:image>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Daily Notes: April 5, 2024</title>
      <link>https://tangentfoxy.github.io/JournalLM/Daily%20Notes%3B%20April%205%2C%202024.html</link>
      <description>These journal entries document the author's daily life, spanning several months. The entries blend personal reflections on health, finances, and relationships with details about hobbies such as tarot card readings and Magic: The Gathering. There are also notes on productivity, including the use of Obsidian note-taking software and attempts at improved organization. Financial tracking, particularly concerning stock performance and spending on card games, is a recurring theme. Finally, the author reflects on learning and knowledge management, expressing a need for improved note organization and deeper engagement with certain topics.</description>
      <enclosure length="8365872" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://tangentfoxy.github.io/JournalLM/Daily%20Notes%3B%20April%205%2C%202024.mp3" />
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 22:00 MST</pubDate>
      <itunes:duration>825</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:episode>1</itunes:episode>
      <itunes:image>https://tangentfoxy.github.io/JournalLM/Daily%20Notes%3B%20April%205%2C%202024.jpg</itunes:image>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
