<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">
  <channel>
    <title>JournalLM</title>
    <link>https://github.com/TangentFoxy/JournalLM/</link>
    <description>I can't believe I'm doing this. Random journals + NotebookLM "podcasts" = this slop.</description>
    <itunes:image>https://tangentfoxy.github.io/JournalLM/podcast-image1400.jpg</itunes:image>
    <item>
      <title>Daily To-Do List &amp; Ideas</title>
      <link>https://tangentfoxy.github.io/JournalLM/Daily%20To-Do%20List%20%26%20Ideas.html</link>
      <description>"The hosts must rhyme every sentence." These journal entries span several months and document the author's creative writing ideas, daily tasks and health management. One entry details a science fiction story concept involving plural systems and a conscious planet. Another focuses on daily to-do lists, including personal errands and medication reminders. A third entry combines personal care routines with tasks related to programming, health testing, and car maintenance, along with musings on video games and creative projects, showcasing the author's diverse interests and attention shifts. The entries reveal a mind actively engaged in multiple pursuits and reflections, revealing their daily struggles and plans.</description>
      <enclosure length="1726786" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://tangentfoxy.github.io/JournalLM/Daily%20To-Do%20List%20%26%20Ideas.mp3" />
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2024 22:10 MST</pubDate>
      <itunes:duration>160</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:episode>5</itunes:episode>
      <itunes:image>https://tangentfoxy.github.io/JournalLM/Daily%20To-Do%20List%20%26%20Ideas.jpg</itunes:image>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Random Knowledge Tidbits and Reflections</title>
      <link>https://tangentfoxy.github.io/JournalLM/Random%20Knowledge%20Tidbits%20and%20Reflections.html</link>
      <description>"You are actually Cortana." These journal entries document the author's daily activities, thoughts, and progress on various projects. Personal reflections include tarot readings, conversations, and emotional responses to books. Professional and creative endeavors encompass software development (including bug fixes and design), writing, and personal knowledge management system refinements. The author grapples with organizational challenges, including managing numerous ideas and improving their note-taking and task management systems. The entries also touch upon broader themes such as the ethical failings of pharmaceutical companies and the nature of power.</description>
      <enclosure length="5578762" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://tangentfoxy.github.io/JournalLM/Random%20Knowledge%20Tidbits%20and%20Reflections.mp3" />
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2024 21:45 MST</pubDate>
      <itunes:duration>550</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:episode>4</itunes:episode>
      <itunes:image>https://tangentfoxy.github.io/JournalLM/Random%20Knowledge%20Tidbits%20and%20Reflections.jpg</itunes:image>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Dangers of AI</title>
      <link>https://tangentfoxy.github.io/JournalLM/The%20Dangers%20of%20AI.html</link>
      <description>These journal entries document the author's experiences with Obsidian, a note-taking application. The entries detail troubleshooting synchronization issues across multiple devices (desktop, iPhone, iPad), including problems with plugins and automatic syncing. The author also reflects on content creation plans, such as a YouTube video, and mentions reading and Minecraft gameplay. Furthermore, concerns about data security related to GitHub syncing are expressed, along with plans for improved note-taking on specific topics. Finally, the author consistently tracks daily tasks and plans in their journal.</description>
      <enclosure length="8591493" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://tangentfoxy.github.io/JournalLM/The%20Dangers%20of%20AI.mp3" />
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2024 15:40 MST</pubDate>
      <itunes:duration>827</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:episode>3</itunes:episode>
      <itunes:image>https://tangentfoxy.github.io/JournalLM/The%20Dangers%20of%20AI.jpg</itunes:image>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2024 Year-End Review &amp; Plans</title>
      <link>https://tangentfoxy.github.io/JournalLM/2024%20Year-End%20Review%20%26%20Plans.html</link>
      <description>These journal entries from November 2023 and January 2024 document the author's daily life, including media consumption (YouTube videos and a film), personal projects (creating custom Magic: The Gathering cards and a technology dependency chart), and self-improvement goals (tracking steps and writing weekly, monthly, and yearly reviews). The entries reveal struggles with maintaining a consistent review schedule and lapses in self-care, along with plans for future tasks and technology-related projects within a Minecraft world. The author also notes missing information and expresses concern about several self-care tasks. The entries show a blend of personal reflections and practical to-do lists.</description>
      <enclosure length="5999693" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://tangentfoxy.github.io/JournalLM/2024%20Year-End%20Review%20%26%20Plans.mp3" />
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 00:00 MST</pubDate>
      <itunes:duration>574</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:episode>2</itunes:episode>
      <itunes:image>https://tangentfoxy.github.io/JournalLM/2024%20Year-End%20Review%20%26%20Plans.jpg</itunes:image>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Daily Notes: April 5, 2024</title>
      <link>https://tangentfoxy.github.io/JournalLM/Daily%20Notes%3B%20April%205%2C%202024.html</link>
      <description>These journal entries document the author's daily life, spanning several months. The entries blend personal reflections on health, finances, and relationships with details about hobbies such as tarot card readings and Magic: The Gathering. There are also notes on productivity, including the use of Obsidian note-taking software and attempts at improved organization. Financial tracking, particularly concerning stock performance and spending on card games, is a recurring theme. Finally, the author reflects on learning and knowledge management, expressing a need for improved note organization and deeper engagement with certain topics.</description>
      <enclosure length="8530828" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://tangentfoxy.github.io/JournalLM/Daily%20Notes%3B%20April%205%2C%202024.mp3" />
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 22:00 MST</pubDate>
      <itunes:duration>825</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:episode>1</itunes:episode>
      <itunes:image>https://tangentfoxy.github.io/JournalLM/Daily%20Notes%3B%20April%205%2C%202024.jpg</itunes:image>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
